Guide to the Leslie Dorsey Collection of Pictorial Clippings 1860-1970 (bulk, 1860-1920) PR 17
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Scrapbooks
  - Broadmoor Hotel Colorado Springs (Offsite-box 51, Folder 3-4)
    Related Materials
    See also Box 17, F. 2
  - NYC Hotels -- "A" to "Pl" (Offsite-box 52, Folder 1-2)
  - NYC Hotels -- "Pl" to "W" (Offsite-box 52, Folder 3-4)
  - Menus designed by Leslie Dorsey (Offsite-box 53, Folder 1)
  - Epicurean Designs by Leslie Dorsey (Offsite-box 53, Folder 2-3)
  - Menus sir! 1856 reception dinner (Offsite-box 54, Folder 1)
  - La Taverna (Offsite-box 54, Folder 2)
  - Rue de la Paix (Offsite-box 54, Folder 3)
  - Circus and Theatre (Offsite-box 55, Folder 1)
  - Circus programs and magazines (Offsite-box 55, Folder 2)
  - Houses (Offsite-box 56, Folder 1-2)
  - Furnishings (Offsite-box 56, Folder 3-4)
  - Victoria Regis and Edward VII (Offsite-box 57, Folder 1-2)
  - People -- African American (Offsite-box 57, Folder 3)
  - People (Offsite-box 57, Folder 4)
  - Steamship Normandie (Offsite-box 58, Folder 1)
  - Trains (Offsite-box 58, Folder 2-4)
  - Ships (Offsite-box 59, Folder 1-3)
  - Sports (Offsite-box 60, Folder 1-4)
  - Christmas greeting cards (Offsite-box 61, Folder 1-2)
  - Christmas Warriors (Offsite-box 61, Folder 3)
  - Once Upon a Christmas (Offsite-box 61, Folder 4)
  - Holiday and Genre Scenes (Offsite-box 62, Folder 1-2)
  - Calling Cards (Offsite-box 62, Folder 3)
  - Victorian Alphabet (Offsite-box 62, Folder 4)
  - Advertising Trade Cards (Offsite-box 63, Folder 1)
  - Centennial Quartette (Offsite-box 63, Folder 2-3)
- Series IV. Collages and graphics
  This series contains a number of collages created by Dorsey from cut-outs and other decorative elements. Dorsey apparently marketed these collages as "Decou-Optiques" to advertisers and other clients for use as a decorative element or for a background. Among the scenes depicted are the 1876 Centennial (possibly used by Dorsey to pitch his book and musical projects), Christmas scenes, winter scenes, and various Western-themed scenes.
  The majority of the collages are in black and white; color collages are identified in the box and folder list. The lettering system is Dorsey's.
  Also included in the series are examples of the materials Dorsey used to create the collages, such as decals and cut-out figures.
  - Collages: Color (Offsite-box 64, Folder 1)
  - Collages: Color, A-K (Offsite-box 64, Folder 2)
  - Collages: Color, L-Y (Offsite-box 64, Folder 3)
  - Collages: Black and White, A-G (Offsite-box 65, Folder 1)
  - Collages: Black and White, H-R (Offsite-box 65, Folder 2)
  - Collages: 1876 Centennial (Offsite-box 65, Folder 3)
  - Collages: 1876 Centennial (folder 2 of 3) (Offsite-box 66, Folder 1)
  - Collages: 1876 Centennial (folder 3 of 3) (Offsite-box 66, Folder 2)
  - Collages: Interior Scenes (Offsite-box 66, Folder 3)
  - Collages: Railroad stations and docks (Offsite-box 66, Folder 4)
  - Collages: Transparencies (Offsite-box 67, Folder 1)
  - Collages: Christmas mockups (Offsite-box 67, Folder 2)
  - Collages: Winter (Offsite-box 67, Folder 3)
  - Collages: Christmas (folder 1 of 5) (Offsite-box 67, Folder 4)
  - Collages: Christmas (folder 2 of 5) (Offsite-box 67, Folder 5)
  - Collages: Christmas (folder 3 of 5) (Offsite-box 67, Folder 6)
  - Collages: Christmas (folder 4 of 5) (Offsite-box 67, Folder 7)
  - Collages: Christmas (folder 5 of 5) (Offsite-box 67, Folder 8)
  - Trade signs, Piazza Prints Inc. (Offsite-box 67, Folder 9)
  - Floral prints, circa 1880's (Offsite-box 68, Folder 3)
  - Advertisements, 1887, 1897-1898, 1906, undated (Offsite-box 68, Folder 4)
  - Illustrations by James Montgomery Flagg (tearsheets), 1907 (Offsite-box 68, Folder 4)
  - Valentines by Dorsey, undated (Offsite-box 68, Folder 5)
  - Gold and silver decals, undated (Offsite-box 68, Folder 6)
  - Animal vignettes, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 1)
  - Greeting cards, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 2)
  - Trade cards, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 3)
  - Victorian chromos, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 4)
  - Bird and feather chromos, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 5)
  - Animal chromos (Offsite-box 69, Folder 6)
  - Playing card stickers; chromos, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 7)
  - Cutouts for collages (Offsite-box 69, Folder 8)
  - Lettering and colored paper, undated (Offsite-box 69, Folder 9)
- Series V. Indexes and professional work
  Dorsey prepared subject indexes for some of his scrapbooks that are included in this series. In addition, there are a few articles and press releases that provide a bit of biographical information, as well as multiple copies of studio photographic portraits of Dorsey. Also included are examples of advertisements and articles from commercial clients of Dorsey that incorporate images from his library.
  - Index to picture collection (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
  - Index to wood engravings (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
  - Subject index, NYC scrapbooks (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - Street index, NYC scrapbooks (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Index, Edwardian Theater in NYC scrapbook (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
  - Index, NYC Hotels scrapbook (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
  - Index, U.S. Resorts and Hotels scrapbooks (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
  - Articles and press releases, 1972, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
  - Advertising campaigns for Morton Frozen Foods and Reynolds Metal Company, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
  - Advertisements for H. Hicks & Sons and other companies, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
  - Design concept for Ogden Foods (Offsite-box 69, Folder 7)
  - Corning Commemorative Series advertising campaign (Offsite-box 63, Folder 3)
  - Good Housekeeping magazine featuring Dorsey artwork, 1972 December (Offsite-box 63, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Leslie Dorsey (Offsite-box 18, Folder 12-13)